<resources>
    <string name="info_1804">In 1804, handlooms functioned through a manual mechanism comprising a wooden frame holding components like heddles, shafts, and warp beams. Heddles, attached to shafts, created sheds through which the weaver passed the weft thread using a shuttle. The beater or reed ensured the weft was evenly packed, while pedals or treadles controlled shaft movement for shed creation.</string>
    <string name="info_1810">The back-strap loom is a simple loom with ancient roots, still used in many cultures around the world (such as Andean textiles). It consists of two sticks or bars between which the warps are stretched. One bar is attached to a fixed object and the other to the weaver, usually by means of a strap around the weavers back. The weaver leans back and uses their body weight to tension the loom.</string>
    <string name="info_1818">During 1818, the first cotton mill was established in India at Fort Gloster near Calcutta by a British merchant named Henry Gourger. About 700,000 lb of yarn was spun here annually. Bowreah Cotton Mills was Indias first cotton cloth mill, established in 1818 by the British at Fort Gloster, located 15 miles south of Calcutta.</string>
    <string name="info_1820">During 1820, most of the Indian weavers had been exported to England for the development of handloom in England. Indians mostly used to farm and the end result was transported to England, leading to advancements in tools and their development. This is the first power loom used in India, made of wood.</string>
    <string name="info_1830">In 1830, using an 1822 patent, Richards Roberts manufactured the first loom with a cast-iron frame, the Roberts loom. The Roberts loom was a cast-iron power loom introduced by Richards Roberts in 1830. It was the first loom that was more viable than a hand loom and was easily adjustable and reliable, which led to its widespread use in the Lancashire cotton industry.</string>
    <string name="info_1842">In 1842, James Bullough and William Kenworthy made the Lancashire Loom. It is a semiautomatic power loom. Although it is self-acting, it has to be stopped to recharge empty shuttles. It was the mainstay of the Lancashire cotton industry for a century, until the Northrop Loom, invented in 1894 with an automatic weft replenishment function, gained ascendancy.</string>
    <string name="info_1844">Howe Sewing Machine by Elias Howe (1844) is the first sewing machine.</string>
    <string name="info_1852">The Northrop Loom replaced the Lancashire Loom after its invention. James Henry Northrop (1894) invented a self-threading shuttle and shuttle spring jaws to hold a bobbin by means of rings on the butt. This paved the way to his automatic filling and changing battery of 1891, the basic feature of the Northrop Loom. The principal advantage of the Northrop Loom was that it was fully automatic; when a warp thread broke, the loom stopped until it was fixed. When the shuttle ran out of thread, Northrops mechanism ejected the depleted pirn and loaded a new full one without stopping.</string>
    <string name="info_1855">It is recorded that in 1855, a Frenchman adapted the Jacquard mechanism to a system by which it could be worked by electromagnets. There was significant interest, but trials were not successful, and the development was soon forgotten. Bonas Textile Machinery NV launched the first successful electronic Jacquard at ITMA Milan in 1983.</string>
    <string name="info_1857">In 1857, a Dutch doctor named Baudouin patented the warp stop mechanism.</string>
</resources>
